

### • DETAILS •

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Mobile No. +971582621655

E-mail

adhham16@gmail.com

Date / Place of birth 1997/09/03 Puttalam, Sri Lanka.

> Nationality Sri Lankan

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/ in/ahamad-adhham

GitHub

https://www.github.com/ adhham16

∘ SKILLS ∘

HTML & CSS

PHP

MySQL

Laravel

jQuery

WordPress

Javascript

Codeigniter

Python

Git

Django

### PROFILE

Full stack developer with four years of complete professional work experience in building modern applications and business solutions. Seeking to secure a role as a full stack developer or engineer at your esteemed company where I can prove my skills in designing, coding, and testing.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Full Stack Engineer at Ali Bin Abdulaziz Investments Co, Dubai, UAE.

February 2022 — Present

- Experience developing REST and Web applications on modern MVC PHP frameworks such as Laravel.
- Working experience with Amazon EC2, Github and Bitbucket.
- Worked in all aspects of WordPress website creation supporting multilingual languages, including design, plug-ins, implementation and SEO.
- Manage a user guide to help and provide technical support to clients understand site features and management of website to increase visitor satisfaction.

# Software Engineer at Imara Software Solutions, Puttalam, Sri Lanka.

June 2020 — November 2021

- Built modern applications using PHP, Laravel, WordPress, and MySQL and supported the company's development and testing processes.
- Maintained repositories for each project using Git.
- Worked with software from a variety of industries, including consumer software, office solutions, healthcare databases, and business solutions.
- Wrote maintainable and extensible code in a team environment.

# Trainee Software Engineer at Imara Software Solutions, Puttalam, Sri Lanka.

November 2019 — June 2020

- Revolve around working to help create websites and web applications using PHP.
- Writing independent piece of codes for ongoing development needs.
- Working as part of a team of developers and report to a Senior Software Engineer.
- Making responsive web pages using HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and jQuery.

## EDUCATION

BEng (Hons) in Software Engineering, University of Westminster.

February 2019 — April 2022

Passed in G.C.E. Advanced Level Examination, P/President's Science College, Puttalam, Sri Lanka.

Index No: 6837220 Year: 2017

### • LANGUAGES •

English

Tamil

Sinhala

## **★** PROJECTS

## **Laravel Projects**

• Speedy- www.speedymoment.com

Designed and developed multiple dashboards and APIs tailored for mobile applications.

Carrier Service

This application is used to store data in a database from an excel file.

• One Padel Method -

Admin dashboard and APIs for mobile applications (Trainer and Trainee).

• Estinara - www.estinara.com

Landing page, Admin and consultant panel with API for mobile application.

• Newme - api.newmegrp.com

Admin and consultant with API for mobile application.

• **Dkko** - www.dkkoapp.com

Admin dashboard with API for mobile application.

• Firstbid - beta.first-bid.com

Vehicle listing website.

• Thabi Al Reem - www.thabialreem.com

Admin and Website with API for mobile application.

#### **Word Press Websites**

- RQ www.the-rq.com
- Newme www.newmegrp.com

## **Other Projects**

Oral Detective (Oral cancer detection system using Image Processing)

This application is used to detect oral cancer with an oral image (RGB).

Technologies - Python, Django (Framework), Python-OpenCV, Keras.

Health Brigade

This application is used to maintain electronic health records an d healthcare databases.

Technologies - PHP, OpenEMR, JavaScript

## COURSES

Introduction to Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2), Amazon Web Services (AWS).

Certificate Course in PHP & MySQL for Beginners, Udemy.

## **¶** REFERENCES

## Dr.Basheer Riskhan Ph.D

Associate Professor Of ICT,

Three Gorges University, Yichang, Hubei, China 443002.

riskhan@yahoo.com

+94714469676 / +8613114451523

#### M.F.Rinsad Ahamed

CEO & Co-founder,

Imara Software Solutions (PVT) LTD, Puttalam, Sri Lanka.

rinsad@imarasoft.net

+94777335857